Jesse Loftus

(619)721-3845

<u>Jesse.Loftus@gmail.com</u> - Website: loftusjl.github.io

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jesse-loftus-861aaa1b - GitHub: https://github.com/loftusjl

Web applications developer with 12 years of experience in database development. Organized professional with secret clearance and 16 years of federal employment. Knowledgeable in hospital equipment management and aircraft rework industries.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

 JavaScript

- React.js
- Node.js
- SQL
- Express.js
- VBA
- Microsoft Access

- HTML5
- CSS
- iQuery
- Handlebars.js
- Bootstrap
- Materialize
- MongoDB

EXPERIENCE

Navy Medical Center San Diego

Equipment Specialist

San Diego, CA Jan 2008–Present

- Provide senior support in acquisition, inventory tracking, and disposal of medical equipment for NMC San Diego and its satellite clinics.
- Develop and maintain a record archival system for all accountable property.
- Lead quarterly meetings with the Hospital Board of Directors to rank and formulate purchasing strategies for the current and upcoming fiscal years.
- Built and currently maintain the Equipment Office Manager (EOM) which has been utilized by the Navy Medicine South West Region since 2011.
 - Provides a digital repository for Joint Commission (JCAHO) and Bureau of Medicine and Surgery (BUMED) Navy audits.
 - Holds 2,980 Command purchase records along with scans of the original purchase request for audit readiness and totals \$231M to-date.
 - Has been used as the equipment receiving system and currently holds records for 29,530 pieces of equipment valued at \$186.7M.
- Developed and maintain Digital Property Book inventory system for Hospital equipment locations.
 - Enabled NMC San Diego to achieve over 98% inventory accuracy (2016) for the first time in over a decade.
 - Holds over 78K records of both active and inactive equipment.
 - Bi-directionally syncs all updated records with end-user laptop and master inventory table.
 - Provides historical location data to assist in future locating of equipment for inventory and/or preventative maintenance.

Fleet readiness center southwest

Production Controller

San Diego, CA Oct 2002-Jan 2008

- Developed and maintained aircraft rework status reporting system which provided dynamic feedback on rework processes for the E2 Hawkeye and C2 Greyhound aircraft.
- Developed and maintained inventory receipt and tracking system for incoming repair parts and the repair part kit deficiencies.
 - Tracked individual component rework and ordering to provide status and date projections for workload scheduling.
 - Coordinated workload with shop foreman based on capabilities and Program Manager established priorities.

EDUCATION

UC San Diego Extension Full-Stack Development

Term GPA: 4.0

May 2018-Present

San Diego, CA

Browser Based Technologies, Java, Quality Assurance, Internet Marketing (SEO and Semantic HTML), Deployment, Databases, Computer Science, Server-Side Development, MERN Stack (React.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Node.js).

Grossmont/ Cuyamaca Community College

San Diego, CA

Term GPA: 3.65

Jan 2011-Present

Introduction to Java Programming, Advanced Composition, Computer Maintenance A+ Certification, Introduction to SQL, Principles/information systems, Web Markup Languages, Databases.

AWARDS

- 2015 Equipment Manager of the Year from the Navy Bureau of Medicine and Surgery.
- 2004 2007 Special Act Awards for systems developed to support aircraft rework efforts from the **Department of the Navy**.

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- 16 years of federal employment.
- 12 years of experience in database development.
- Hold secret clearance since 2008.
- Knowledgeable in hospital equipment management.
- Experienced in aircraft rework industries.